A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Religious Interests, Series N FA323
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Religious Organizations
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Contributions, 1953-1955 (Box 61, Folder 481)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Contributions, 1953-1955 (Box 61, Folder 481A)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Contributions, 1960-1962 (Box 61, Folder 482)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Contributions, 1959-1961 (Box 61, Folder 482A)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Contributions, 1956-1960 (Box 61, Folder 483)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Clippings, 1946-1959 (Box 62, Folder 484)
    Also contribution, pertinent facts, financial statements, minutes, by-laws.
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America (NCCC) - Printed Material (Report) - "The Case for New York" (Box 62, Folder 485)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ, USA - Proposed Religious Center
    Plans for Center on Morningside Heights (headquarters National Council of Churches of Christ). John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions, laying the cornerstone, Dwight Eisenhower. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., R. J. McCracken, F. S. Harmon, D. Eisenhower.
    141.821
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 486)
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 486A)
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1955-1958 (Box 62, Folder 487)
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1949-1958 (Box 62, Folder 487A)
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 488)
    - Religious Organizations - NCCC - Proposed Religious Center, 1954 (Box 62, Folder 489)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ, USA - Proposed Religious Center - Clippings and Letters of Appreciation, 1955-1959 (Box 63, Folder 490)
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ, USA - Proposed Religious Center - 1954 Pledge Fund, 1954-1959 (Box 63, Folder 491)
    Selection of permanent headquarters site, preliminary building plans, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer to donate funds for site near Columbia University. Correspondents include Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Religious Organizations - National Council of the Churches of Christ, USA - Proposed Religious Center - 1954 Pledge Fund (Box 63, Folder 491A)
  - Religious Organizations - Interchurch Center - Dedication, 1960-1962 (Box 63, Folder 492)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s $5,000 gift for plaque. John D. Rockefeller 3rd's dedication speech.
  - Religious Organizations - Interchurch Center - Dedication, 1959-1960 (Box 63, Folder 492A)
  - Religious Organizations - Interchurch Center - Architectural Material Received from Dana S. Creel's Office, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 493)
    Plans, drawings, photo of, comment. Correspondents include Harold Willis, Dana S. Creel.
  - Religious Organizations - Interchurch Center - Architectural Material Received from Dana S. Creel's Office, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 494)
  - Religious Organizations - Religion in American Life, 1950-1951 (Box 64, Folder 495)
    Work, printed items, Rockefeller Brothers Fund grant. Correspondents include Charles E. Wilson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Karl Quimbey.
    141.83
  - Religious Organizations - Religion in American Life - Contributions, 1951-1954 (Box 64, Folder 496)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donation to program, renewal of contribution. Correspondents include K. Quimbey, Dana S. Creel.
  - Religious Organizations - Religion in American Life - Contributions, 1951-1954 (Box 64, Folder 496A)
  - Religious Organizations - Young Christian Workers, 1951-1953 (Box 64, Folder 497)
    Plans for Monsignor Cardijn's visit to the United States, budget work, Laurance S. Rockefeller's anonymous gift. Correspondents include Paul Van Zeeland, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Patrick Keegan.
    141.85
  - Religious Organizations - New York State Council of Churches, 1940-1961 (Box 64, Folder 498)
    Denial of pleas for contribution, printed letters. Correspondents include W. T. Clemens, Arthur W. Packard.
    141.86
  - Religious Organizations - American Council of Christian Churches, 1943-1955 (Box 64, Folder 499)
    Newspaper clippings.
    141.87
- Riverside Church
  - Riverside Church - Church Property, 1925-1926 (Box 64, Folder 500)
    Acquisition of Pierce property on Riverside Drive. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
    230
  - Riverside Church - Fitzgerald Property, 1925-1954 (Box 64, Folder 501)
    Acquisition of property owned by Mrs. Mary A. Fitzgerald; transfer of deed to Riverside Church, 1935. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Riverside Church - New Church - Architects - Cram; McKim, Mead and White; York and Sawyer, 1925-1937 (Box 64, Folder 502)
    Ralph A. Cram: Preliminary sketches; cost estimates for new buildings. Correspondents include Ralph Adams Cram, John Russell Pope, E. L. Ballard. McKim, Mead & White, and York and Sawyer: Preliminary estimates of the cubic space contents required for new church. Correspondents include Burt L. Fenner, Philip Sawyer.
    230A
  - Riverside Church - Addition, 1955 - Collens, 1955-1956 (Box 65, Folder 503)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s interest in addition. Correspondents include Harold Willis, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John B. Trevor.
    230A1
  - Riverside Church - Addition - Dedication and Offer, 1955-1959 (Box 65, Folder 504)
    Church reception of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s offer of new South Wing. Dedication: John D. Rockefeller 3rd represented John D. Rockefeller, Jr. at ceremonies.
  - Riverside Church - Addition - Pledge, 1955-1958 (Box 65, Folder 505)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gave $15,000,000; over $13,000,000 used on South Wing.
  - Riverside Church - Addition, 1955, 1956-1960 (Box 65, Folder 506)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s decision to build church addition. Studies of cost and maintenance. Design and construction; steel supply problem. Completion; comments on completed work. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George J. Heidt, John A. Krout, Dana S. Creel.
  - Riverside Church - Addition, 1955, 1951-1956 (Box 65, Folder 507)
  - Riverside Church - Addition - Claremont Avenue Exit, 1956-1957 (Box 65, Folder 508)
    Gymnasium building. Gift of property by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include George J. Heidt, Dana S. Creel, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Riverside Church - Church Monthly and Church Weekly, 1930-1952 (Box 66, Folder 509)
    Various issues of "The Church Monthly," January 1944 to December 1947; Rockefeller subscriptions; underwriting of publication costs of the "Weekly." Publication of Fosdick's sermons. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George J. Heidt, George K. Weeks.
    230B
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Contract, 1927-1933 (Box 66, Folder 510)
    Technical specifications, modifications and additions to contract, blueprints of control system, engineering data. Recasting of existing bells, casting of Bourdon bell. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, William R. Conklin, Frederick Mayer, Cyril F. Johnston.
    230C
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Contract - Letters Regarding Payments, 1927-1929 (Box 66, Folder 511)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s payments. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. R. Conklin, F. Mayer, C. F. Johnston.
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box 66, Folder 512)
    Mayer's article on carillons; experimentations in transmittal of the sound; blueprints of clavier mechanism; Riverbank Laboratories report on carillons; technical and financial data on the recasting of the Bourdon bells; remission of carillon import duty. Installation of the Park Avenue church carillon and bells at Riverside; tuning of the bells; inaugural recitals on December 24 and 25, 1930.
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1930-1949 (Box 66, Folder 513)
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 66, Folder 514)
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence - Transmission of Sound to Auditorium, 1927-1931 (Box 66, Folder 515)
    Dayton C. Miller's report on "The Reproduction of Carillon Music," January 18, 1928, suggesting use of elevator shafts for transmitting the sound. Correspondents include D. C. Miller, F. Mayer, W. R. Conklin, C. F. Johnston.
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1950-1956 (Box 67, Folder 516)
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1927-1935 (Box 67, Folder 517)
    Amplification by Mr. Bludworth. 1935. Experimentation with amplifying the carillon.
    Cologne Bell. 1928. Unsuccessful attempts to record the tone of the Cologne Cathedral Bell. Correspondents include George J. Heidt.
    Dampers - Mr. Giannini. 1930-1935. Improvement of carillon tones; installation of the device. Technical and engineering aspects. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. M. Giannini, F. Mayer, George Heidt.
    Inscription. 1930. "In Loving Memory of My Mother...." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    Professor D. C. Miller Report. 1927-1931. Report on European bell towers.
  - Riverside Church - Carillon Correspondence, 1925-1949 (Box 67, Folder 518)
    William Gorham Rice. 1928. Publication of "Carillon Music and Singing Towers of the Old World and the New" by W. G. Rice.
    Arthur C. J. Roy. 1928-1930. Contract for the Roy device for oscillating of church bells.
    Work on the Carillon, 1939. 1939-1949. Care and maintenance, retuning problems. Correspondents include F. Mayer, A. L. Scott, C. F. Johnston.
  - Riverside Church - Carillon - Lefevre Contract Pledge, 1927-1960 (Box 67, Folder 519)
    Employment of Lefevre; gifts of money by John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Playing of Laura Spelman Rockefeller's favorite hymns. Lefevre's illness; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s concern, gift. Correspondents include Kamiel Lefevre, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George J. Heidt.
    230C1
  - Riverside Church - Carillon - Lefevre Contract Pledge, 1929-1934 (Box 67, Folder 519A)
    Contract, September 17, 1929. Lefevre appointed carilloneur. Correspondents include Lefevre, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt.
    Pledges, October 2, 1929 and April 8, 1933. 1929-1933. Payment of Lefevre salary. Correspondents include Lefevre, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt.
  - Riverside Church - Centennial Celebration, 1940-1941 (Box 67, Folder 520)
    Arrangements for celebration, retirement allowances for ministers and church operating staff, publication of centennial history, letters of thanks for participation in program. Correspondents include Mrs. Charles Poletti, Nicholas Murray Butler, A. E. Bestor, Miss Grace Patton, H. E. Fosdick, Harry P. Fish, G. Heidt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Lawrence Tibbett, Grace Moore, Kamiel Lefevre, Albert Spalding, T. Raymond St. John, Benjamin M. Day, James C. Colgate, Noel T. Dowling.
    230C3
  - Riverside Church - Centennial Celebration/100th Anniversary - Printed Material, 1943-1963 (Box 68, Folder 521)
  - Riverside Church - Rev. E. C. Carder, 1943-1963 (Box 68, Folder 522)
    Carder's History of the Riverside Church, in manuscript. 1941 anniversary celebration; stained glass windows of Riverside Church; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s gifts, help in purchase of home in Vermont for Carder; Carder's letters of thanks. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. C. Carder.
    230C2
  - Riverside Church - Rev. E. C. Carder, 1943 (Box 68, Folder 522A)
  - Riverside Church - Rev. E. C. Carder, 1930-1942 (Box 68, Folder 523)
  - Riverside Church - John D. Rockefeller Fund, 1933-1938 (Box 68, Folder 524)
    Establishment of endowment for maintenance of Memorial Carillon and Building, stipulations upon usage of the fund, subsequent modifications and investments; addition to fund in 1958. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. R. Conklin, G. J. Heidt, Winthrop Aldrich.
    230C6
  - Riverside Church - John D. Rockefeller Fund, 1940-1959 (Box 68, Folder 525)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1949-1959 (Box 69, Folder 526)
    Unemployment relief, salary adjustments, gifts for current and non-recurring church expenses, underwriting of deficit in budget; Morningside Heights Cooperative Housing Project. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt, H. E. Fosdick, W. T. Gossett, A. L. Scott, T. Raymond St. John.
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1929-1933 (Box 69, Folder 527)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - June 21, 1932, 1932-1948 (Box 69, Folder 528)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - July 3, 1934, 1934-1936 (Box 69, Folder 529)
    Establishment of Rockefeller Budget Fund; implementation of the original gift. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A. L. Scott, G. J. Heidt, W. R. Conklin.
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Gift from Laura Spelman Rockefeller's Estate, 1932 (Box 69, Folder 530)
    Transfer of securities and cash. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. L. Ballard, J. C. Colgate.
  - Riverside Church - Contributions and Gifts - John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Martha Baird Rockefeller Contributions, 1960-1961 (Box 69, Folder 531)
    Year end gifts.
  - Riverside Church - Miscellaneous Contributions, 1930-1961 (Box 69, Folder 532)
    Underwriting church deficits; report by Mark M. Jones on budgetary structure, current problems and future proposals, February 1, 1939. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Norris L. Tibbetts, T. R. St. John.
  - Riverside Church - Miscellaneous Contributions - Christmas Fund - Women's Society, 1929-1945 (Box 70, Folder 533)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt, W. S. Richardson.
  - Riverside Church - Miscellaneous Contributions - Unemployment Funds, 1931-1934 (Box 70, Folder 534)
    Pledges for workroom at church. Correspondents include H. E. Fosdick, G. J. Heidt, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Riverside Church - Riverside Fund to Help Build a Christian World, 1947-1961 (Box 70, Folder 535)
    Purpose and importance of the fund, memo on family interests in church finances, acknowledgements of gifts made. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt, Arthur W. Packard, N. L. Tibbetts.
    230C61
  - Riverside Church - Budgets
    Family contributions to budget. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, G. J. Heidt, A. L. Scott.
    230C7
    - Riverside Church - Budgets, 1929-1942 (Box 70, Folder 536)
    - Riverside Church - Budgets, 1941-1950 (Box 70, Folder 537)
    - Riverside Church - Budgets, 1951-1956 (Box 70, Folder 538)
    - Riverside Church - Budgets, 1946-1952 (Box 70, Folder 538A)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People, 1932-1960 (Box 70, Folder 539)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s appeals for contributions and letters of thanks. Correspondents include W. Aldrich, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, James F. Hoge, Hunter Marston, Miss Stillman, Mrs. Elon Hooker, G. J. Heidt, Mrs. I. H. Pardee (nee Abby Rockefeller), Mrs. E. S. Harkness, Mrs. K. M. Ladd, Grace Moore Parera.
    230C8
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1952 Appeal Letters for 1953 Budget, 1952-1953 (Box 70, Folder 540)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1951 Appeal Letters for 1952 Budget, 1951-1952 (Box 70, Folder 541)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1950 Appeal Letters for 1951 Budget, 1950-1951 (Box 71, Folder 542)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1949 Appeal Letters for 1950 Budget, 1949-1950 (Box 71, Folder 543)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1948 Appeal Letters for 1949 Budget, 1948-1949 (Box 71, Folder 544)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1947 Appeal Letters for 1948 Budget, 1947-1948 (Box 71, Folder 545)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1946 Appeal Letters for 1947 Budget (Box 71, Folder 546)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1955 Appeal Letters for 1956 Budget, 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 547)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1954 Appeal Letters for 1955 Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 71, Folder 548)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s appeals for contributions and letters of thanks. Correspondents include W. Aldrich, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, James F. Hoge, Hunter Marston, Miss Stillman, Blanche Hooker (mother of Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller), G. J. Heidt, Abby Rockefeller Pardee, Mrs. E. S. Harkness, Mrs. K. M. Ladd, Grace Moore Parera.
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1954 Appeal Letters for 1955 Budget, 1954-1955 (Box 71, Folder 548A)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1953 Appeal Letters for 1954 Budget, 1953-1954 (Box 71, Folder 549)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1959 Appeal Letters for 1960 Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 71, Folder 550)
    Open per KWR, January 2005.
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1958 Appeal Letters for 1959 Budget, 1958-1959 (Box 71, Folder 551)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1957 Appeal Letters for 1958 Budget, 1957-1958 (Box 71, Folder 552)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1956 Appeal Letters for 1957 Budget, 1956-1957 (Box 71, Folder 553)
  - Riverside Church - Contributions from Various People - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1956 Appeal Letters for 1957 Budget, 1923-1931 (Box 72, Folder 554)
  - Riverside Church - Current Contributions to Capitalization Fund, 1944-1945 (Box 72, Folder 555)
    Creation of Consolidation Fund, holding of balance of John D. Rockefeller's gifts; provision for addition of future legacies to the fund. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. R. Conklin, W. T. Gossett.
    230C10
  - Riverside Church - Carillon - F. C. Mayer - Expenses, 1922-1937 (Box 72, Folder 556)
    Statement of expenses abroad to hear bells and organs in four countries, 1922; to inspect Park Avenue Baptist Church carillon, 1925; testing, 1928; conferences regarding the Riverside Church carillon. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel, F. Mayer, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    230C12
  - Riverside Church - New Church - Marc Eidlitz and Sons, 1926-1932 (Box 72, Folder 557)
    Estimates of cost of certain phases of construction, lightning protection, report on fire damage. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., E. L. Ballard, Marc Eidlitz & Sons, Inc.
    230E
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick Correspondence, 1925-1956 (Box 72, Folder 558)
    Calling of Dr. Fosdick, his advice on construction of the building, severance of his connections with Union Theological Seminary, plans for 1941 centennial; reactions to his sermons and retirement. Comment on biography. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. E. Fosdick.
    230F
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick Correspondence - Confidential Letters, 1925 (Box 72, Folder 559)
    Fosdick's theological beliefs; location and erection of church, financial arrangements. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. E. Fosdick, E. L. Ballard.
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick Correspondence - Sermon - April 2, 1944 (Box 72, Folder 560)
    Publication of "Facing Life's Central Test."
  - Riverside Church - Ministers - Possible Successors to Dr. Fosdick, 1941-1946 (Box 72, Folder 561)
    Possible successors to Fosdick; biographical sketches and sermons by these men; calling of Norris L. Tibbetts. Correspondents include C. W. Pettit (Chairman of Pulpit Committee), John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard, A. L. Scott.
  - Riverside Church - Fire - December 21, 1928, 1928-1931 (Box 72, Folder 562)
    Report by the New York Board of Fire Underwriters, January 15, 1929; letters of sympathy; the fire loss account. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., G. J. Heidt, W. R. Conklin, Rev. Francis C. Duffy, Theodore F. Green, W. L. Mackenzie King.
    230F1
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick's Peace Sermon - Miscellaneous Letters - Booklet, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 563)
    Reaction to publication of "Dare We Break the Vicious Circle of Fighting Evil with Evil?" Correspondents include H. E. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., T. J. Ross.
    230F2
  - Riverside Church - Distribution of Dr. Fosdick's Sermon, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 564)
  - Riverside Church - Dr. H. E. Fosdick - Distribution of Peace Pamphlet, 1939 (Box 73, Folder 565)
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Harry E. Fosdick - Retirement, 1942-1946 (Box 73, Folder 566)
    Notes for John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s speech at Fosdick farewell party, May 22, 1946; programs, clippings. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. E. Fosdick, N. L. Tibbetts, Dr. R. J. McCracken.
    230F3
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick's Retirement - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Address, 1942-1946 (Box 73, Folder 567)
  - Riverside Church - Dr. Fosdick's Report on Policy and Program - October 1947 (Box 73, Folder 568)
    Summary of philosophy behind church policies since 1926 (John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s and Fosdick's marked copy). Correspondents include H. E. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    230F4
  - Riverside Church - General
    Construction of building, calling of Dr. Fosdick, staff salaries and expenses, demography of area adjacent to church, organization dates of church corporation, installation of Rev. J. Gordon Chamberlin, mission in the Belgian Congo, tickets of admission to services, reports of Benevolence Committee, Rev. Jesse Lyon. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel, W. R. Conklin, G. J. Heidt, H. E. Fosdick, E. L. Ballard, Dr. Hellstrom.
    230G
    - 1925-1936 (Box 73, Folder 569)
    - 1937-1948 (Box 73, Folder 570)
    - 1948-1961 (Box 74, Folder 571)
    - 1960 (Box 74, Folder 571A)
    - 1949-1956 (Box 74, Folder 572)
  - Riverside Church - General - Baptism Question, 1925 (Box 74, Folder 573)
    Retention of name "Baptist" in church title; Dr. Fosdick's views on pouring and sprinkling as methods of baptism. Correspondents include H. E. Fosdick, Cornelius Woelfkin, Dr. Eugene C. Carder.
  - Riverside Church - General - Board of Ushers, 1930-1948 (Box 74, Folder 574)